hintsandthings.co.uk 2016-12-19

# Privacy and Cookie Policy for www.hintsandthings.com

**

* * *

At www.hintsandthings.com, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by www.hintsandthings.com and how it is used. 

Hints and Things do not collect or use for commercial purposes, personal information such as names or addresses when you visit the site. If, however, you contact us by email, we will retain and use your email address solely to reply to your contact and for no other purpose. If you choose to provide other personal information such as your name and address, that information will only be used to fulfil your request for information.

We do, however, use **third-party advertising** companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and would like to know your options in relation to not having this information used by these companies, [ click here.](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)

**Log Files**

Like many other Web sites, www.hintsandthings.com makes use of log files. 

The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track users movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. 

Hints and Things uses Matrixstats as an analysis tool, **** however this system does not use "cookies" and instead collates information taken from the server log for our domain. 

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

www.hintsandthings.com **does not use** 1st party cookies. 

We do, however, publish Google Adsense interest-based advertisements on our website. These are tailored by Google to reflect your interests. To determine your interests, Google will track your behaviour across the web using cookies. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser using Google's Ads Preference Manager, available at: [ www.google.com/ads/preferences/](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/). 

You can opt-out of the Adsense partner network cookie at: [ www.google.com/privacy_ads.html](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). However, this opt-out mechanism uses a cookie, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained. To ensure that an opt-out is maintained in respect of a particular browser, you should use the Google browser plug-in available at: [ www.google.com/ads/preferences/plugin](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/plugin).

Most browsers allow you to reject all cookies, whilst some browsers allow you to reject just third party cookies. For example, in Internet Explorer you can refuse all cookies by clicking "Tools", "Internet Options", "Privacy", and selecting "Block all cookies" using the sliding selector. Blocking all cookies will, however, have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.

**DoubleClick DART Cookie**

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site. 

Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet. 

**Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie** by visiting the [ Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.co.uk/privacy_ads.html).

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on [ www.hintsandthings.com](http://www.hintsandthings.com/).  

  * Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to www.hintsandthings.com and other sites on the Internet.   

  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL - [ http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html)

Some of our advertising partners or service suppliers may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our partners include:-

> Google Adsense 
> 
> Book Depository - see [ http://www.bookdepository.com/help/topic/HelpId/20/Our-privacy-policy#helpContent](http://www.bookdepository.com/help/topic/HelpId/20/Our-privacy-policy#helpContent)
> 
> Findmeplants.co.uk

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on www.hintsandthings.com sent directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see. 

www.hintsandthings.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. 

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. www.hintsandthings.com's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites. 

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options (see [ http://www.aboutcookies.org/how-to-delete-cookies/](http://www.aboutcookies.org/how-to-delete-cookies/)  More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites, [ http://www.aboutcookies.org/how-to-control-cookies/](http://www.aboutcookies.org/how-to-control-cookies/) or <http://wiht.link/cookiesguide>  If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at june@hintsandthings.com. 

****

**June Jackson**

* * *

Copyright 2000-2013 Hints and Things  
All Rights Reserved.

No portion of this site may be reproduced or redistributed without prior written permission from Hints and Things. All trademarks & copyrights throughout Hints and Things remain the property of their respective owners.

Hints and Things cannot be held responsible for any information given on this site nor do they necessarily agree with, or endorse, the views given by third parties.

**
